# William Okech

Phone: +254-716-309048 | Email: willyokech@gmail.com |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamokech/ | GitHub: https://github.com/wokech

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Research scientist with 10+ years of experience working in public health and engineering. Strong technical skills in statistics, programming, image processing and analysis, and data visualization. Professional interests include extracting meaningful insights from raw data and using disparate data sources to generate compelling visualizations.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. Biomedical Engineering, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York M.S. Biomedical Engineering, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York MSc Biomedical Engineering, University of Oxford, Oxford, England B.S.E. Bioengineering, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

October 2015 May 2012 September 2010 May 2008

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Statistics for Biomedical Research: R and RStudio (4 years) | PRISM (4 years) Programming for Biomedical Applications: MATLAB (4 years) | Python (2 years) Biomedical Image Processing and Analysis: CellProfiler (3 years) | Fiji / ImageJ (10 years)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (SCIENTIFIC REVIEW AND EDITING)

Scientific Editor, Charlesworth Author Services **Reviewer**, Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy

February 2020-Present August 2019-Present

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (TEACHING)

Graduate Teaching Assistant, University of Rochester

- Introduction to Biomedical Engineering (BME 100)
- Biomedical Computation and Statistics (BME 221)

September 2011-May 2012

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (RESEARCH)

Postdoctoral Research Associate, University of Pittsburgh Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Johns Hopkins University Postdoctoral Research Associate, University of Rochester Graduate Research Assistant, University of Rochester Graduate Research Assistant, Botnar Research Centre, University of Oxford Undergraduate Research Assistant, Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania

November 2017-September 2019 September 2016-September 2017 October 2015-June 2016 September 2010-August 2015 June 2010-August 2010 June 2007-September 2008

## PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Biomedical Engineering Society
- Certified Carpentries Instructor (Data and Software)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Please refer to Google Scholar Profile

#### HONORS, AWARDS, AND SERVICE

- Judge for the International Genetically Engineered Machines (iGEM) Competition; 2021
- Judge for the LATAM International Genetically Engineered Machines (iGEM) Design League Competition; 2021
- Grand Award Judge for the Intel International Science and Engineering Fair, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; 2018
- Computational modeling "Finding Your Inner Modeler" Travel Award (National Science Foundation; 2017 & 2018)
- Bioengineering Senior Design Award (University of Pennsylvania; 2008)
- Dean's List (University of Pennsylvania: 2007–2008)

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request